jameschadek10@gmail.com • 425-512-4666 <u>LinkedIn</u> • Maple Valley, WA

James Chadek

Skilled IT Project Manager and IT Service Desk Technician

Accomplished IT support specialist, project manager, and leader with over 3 years of progressive experience facilitating the success of organizations through efficient technological support services. Successfully resolved countless customer-facing issues in an efficient manner, as well as being fluent in a variety of software programs.

Proficiencies

Technical Java (2 years), SQL (1 year), C++/Obj. C (1 year), Python II (less than a year), Microsoft Office Suite, **Expertise** Zoom/Google Hangouts/Skype/Discord, Oracle SQL Developer, Apache Hadoop/Hbase/PIG, Windows

XP/Vista/7/8.1/10, Ubuntu Linux 18/Kali Linux, MacOS, Virtual Box

NonTechnical
Expertise

Cloud Computing, Information Management Systems, Project Management, IT Support, Communication,
Deadline Management, Working Independently, Leadership, Schedule Management, Customer Service Issue
Resolution, Vendor Management, Computer Hardware Management, IT Infrastructure Support

Education, Certifications, and Activities

Bachelor of Arts in Management Information Systems, University of Idaho, Graduated in May 2020

• Earned Dean's List Honors 5 out of 8 semesters (including both senior year semesters).

Relevant Experience from College Projects

RDF Demonstration with SQL Developer, University of Idaho: Data Mgmt. for Big Data **04/2020**

Led a 3-person team in the technical implementation of framework utilizing SQL. Put together and performed a 15-minute lecture about the installation of software, creating a semantic data network, and model creation.

• Used business case examples to show how this is advantageous to companies with big data needs.

Technical Lead for a GPA Calculator App, University of Idaho: App Development 10/2019 to 12/2019 Managed the development of an application utilizing the MIT App Inventory, leveraging Scratch-like logic blocks.

• As the technical lead of a 3-person team, spearheaded the collaboration between parties on the project.

Inventory Database, University of Idaho: Database Design

08/2017 to 10/2019

Directed the design of an Oracle database in SQL Developer and Data Modeler. Performed a total cost of ownership analysis with an additional overview of integration.

Partnered with the client to best understand their needs and to create a customized end-product.

CALS Computing Assistant, University of Idaho

08/2015 to 12/2015

Was accountable for the reformatting and overall management of staff computers. Effectively implemented Windows operating system change with included security updates, as well as other software packages.

• Played a role in limited server maintenance, as well as assisted helpdesk-like support to end-

Certifications: MTA: Windows Operating System Fundamentals Certification (2015), CompTIa A+ Certification (Ongoing) **Personal Project:** In the process of constructing a Linux-based Minecraft server & have built every desktop owned.

Relevant Career Experience

Hardware Tester/Sales Floor, RE-PC Tukwila

11/2020 to Present

Act as a critical on-site resource in the assistance of clients, as well as oversee the help desk and sales floor. Perform a wide variety of testing on all different kinds of hardware and peripherals. Create and manage numerous systems while leveraging deployable operating systems. Coordinate high-dollar inventory processes.

- Direct Tier 1 support, as well as carry-out on-site repairs and upgraded problems.
- Managed several systems which helped reduce the number of returns and increase efficiency.

Further Career Experience

Landscaper, Cobblestone Landscaping LLC. Package Handler, FedEx Ground Administrative Assistant, University of Idaho

08/2016 to 08/2019 06/2016 to 08/2016 01/2016 to 05/2016